Now that we're getting to more complex queries using Subqueries,
由于我们讲到使用子查询进行更加复杂的查询
the classroom workspace may seem a bit cramped.
课堂工作空间可能看起来有些狭促
If you've not already been writing your queries in an editor,
如果你还没有在编辑器中编写查询
now is a great time to start. Here's my workflow.
那么现在是开始的好时机 接下来是我的工作流程
You can see over here on the left,
你可以看到在左边
I have my editor open with the subqueries.sql extension.
我的编辑器使用 subqueries.sql 扩展名打开
And then over here on the right, is the classroom,
然后右边的这个位置是课堂
where I can read the questions and execute my code.
在那里我可以阅读问题并执行我的代码
So, now let's take a look at this first question.
现在我们来看第一个问题
It says provide the name of the sales rep in
第一个问题是
each region with the largest amount of total USD sales.
请提供各个地区销售总额最大的销售代表的名字
In order to solve this problem,
要解决这个问题
let's first try to pull some of this information together.
我们首先可尝试拉取一些信息
We can see that the sales rep information exists in this table.
这个表给出的是销售代表信息
The region information is over here,
这个表是区域信息
and the total amount USD is over here in the orders table.
美元总额在这里的订单表中
Therefore we need to join these four tables
因此需要将这四个表综合在一起
together in order to pull all this information together.
以拉取这些信息
So, let's go ahead and start.
那么我们开始
Start with a comment.
首先是注释的起始标识
Okay, so that should
好
make it easier to find that stuff when I come back.
当我回头看的时候 它能使我更容易地找到这些东西
And let's go ahead and start tackling this problem.
接下来 继续解决这个问题
So, we want to pool all this information together.
把所有这些信息汇集在一起
So, let's go ahead and start with the sales rep table.
我们从销售代表表格开始
I'll label that with an alias of SR. Let's join the region table,
将其别名标注为 sr 然后跟区域表联接
I'll label that with an alias of R. We want to
区域表用别名 r 标注
join this where the primary and foreign keys match,
主键和外键匹配　然后联接
and so therefore that's just like SR region ID is equal to r.id.
那么 sr.region_id = r.id
And then if we want to pull the accounts information,
要拉取账户信息
I'll have an alias of A and we want a sales rep id equal to sr.id.
使用别名 a 那么就是 a.sales_rep_id = sr.id
And then let's join the orders table and we'll join now
然后联接订单表
on o.account id equal to a.id.
o.account_id = a.id
Cool. So, now we sort of have all of our information pulled together.
很好 现在我们把所有的信息都汇总到一起了
We can see from the query we're going to need the name of the sales rep,
从该查询可以看到 我们需要销售代表的姓名、区域名称
the region, and then the total amount of sales for each of these reps.
以及每个代表的总销售额
So, let's go ahead and just pull some of that information together.
所以继续　把这些信息放在一起
So, if we pull the sales rep information,
如果我们能汇总销售代表信息
and then we can pull the region information,
那么我们也可以汇总区域信息
and then the orders.
以及订单信息
We want the total amount,
我们需要总金额
and we need that basically for each rep we want.
和基本上每个代表的总金额
The sum of this. So, let's just call that total sales.
销售总额 即 total_sales
And then we're going to want to group by the things that aren't in our alias.
然后要对不在我们别名之列的东西进行分组
So, our alias is right here,
别名在这里
and we have these two columns that are outside of it.
这两个列在它们之外
I'll just do One comma two,
那么分组条件是　1　2
and we might do an order by the third descending let's say.
然后 ORDER BY 3 DESC
Let's go ahead and run this,
让我们继续
see what we get.
看看得到了什么
Cool.
很好
So, it looks like that executed.
执行完成
You can see we only got one name column back,
可以看到我们只有一个名字列
and that's probably because,
这可能是因为
the workspace is confused about having these two columns named the same thing.
工作空间对于将这两列名称相同感到不解
So, let's be more explicit.
因此 我们可以使它们更加具体
Let's just call this rep, name, and region.
我们称之为rep_name和region_name
Let's try that again.
这样再试一次
Cool.
很好
So, now we got three of them.
现在出现的是三列
We have the rep, the region, and the total sales.
包括销售代表名字、区域名称、总销售额
But for this question,
但是这个问题
we want to provide the name of the sales rep in
要求我们提供的销售代表
each region with the largest amount of total sales.
应该是各区域销售总额最大的那位
So basically, what we want for the Southeast region is we want
所以从根本上说
this individual for the Northeast region we want this individual,
在东南地区 我们要的是这个人 东北地区我们要的是这个人
but here we have
但是这里还有另一个东南地区的销售代表
another Southeast region person we don't want them showing up in our table.
但我们并不希望他出现在我们的表格里
This person should be for the West,
这位应该是西方区域总额最高的销售代表
and then any other regions that we have we basically just want that top individual.
其他区域同理 我们只想看到相应的销售冠军
So, in order to do this,
要做到这一点
we're going to have to do a tricky join,
需要进行稍微复杂的联接
but this is pretty common.
但这很常见
Basically, we have the information from this table and we like that.
从这里可以看到表格信息
So we're going to create a subquery.
接下来我们要创建一个子查询
And I'm just going to call this t1.
暂且称它为 t1
We could probably come up with a better naming convention for that.
或者大家可以提出更好的命名规则
But, we want to pull from t1 and then basically what we want to do,
我们想要从 t1 提取信息 然后要做的
is we want to select the region.
是选择地区
So, for each region we just want the maximum total sales.
对于每个地区 我们只想看到总销售额最大的销售代表
So, from this table that we just looked at that one exists right here,
所以从刚刚看到的右边这张表中
we're going to pull the region along with the max total sales for that region.
我们将提取相应地区的最大总销售额
And because this is already grouped by the individual,
由于已经对个人进行分组
we're just going to get the max number over here for each region.
我们只需提取每个地区的最大销售额
So, for Southeast that should just pull this number,
所以对于东南区域 应该提取这个数字
and for Northeast it should just pull this number.
对于东北区域 应该提取这个数字
And for the West,
对于西部区域
it should pull this number and then it'll keep looking.
应该提取这个数字 以此类推
And then you can see we have this Northeast region,
可以看到东北区域
and so it should just pull this max one,
应该提取这个最大额
and all the rest of these should go away.
除了提取部分 其余都会消失
Unfortunately, we can't do this all at once,
遗憾的是 我们不能一蹴而就
because if we group by the individual again,
因为如果我们再次对个人进行分组
the individual along with the region is still
那么该地区相应的个人仍然是独一无二的
unique so we'd end up with all of these table values back.
所以我们最终又会看到所有这些表值
But if we grew by just the region, and we pull the max,
但如果只对地区分组
we should only get the one rep with the maximum amount of sales.
我们应该只得到销售额最大的一个销售代表
So, that's what we're going to do in this table.
因此接下来我们应该这样来做
So, this is the max sales for the region because we have another aggregate up here,
这是该地区的最大销售额
we're going to need to group by anything that's not in the aggregate.
由于我们在这里有另一个聚合 我们需要对不在聚合内的东西进行分组
So, it's just this first thing.
这只是其一
Well let's go ahead and run this, make sure that it works.
好 我们继续运行它 确保它是有效的
Cool. So, now what you're seeing is we have these four regions,
很好 现在可以看到这四个地区
and I think I said the wrong thing about the Northeast earlier.
前面提到东北区域的时候我出了一点差错 （导致出现两个东北区域）
We have these four regions each with their max sales,
现在我们得到了四个地区以及各地区的最大销售额
and essentially what we want to do is we want to match that back to the original table.
接下来我们将它与原来的表相结合
We want to match that to the table that we had before,
与之前的表相结合
where the regions match as well as where the total sales,
匹配地区
is equal to the max sales.
总销售额等于最大销售额
So, let's go ahead and do that.
我们继续
So, we have this table,
我们得到这个表
that's this one that exists over here on the right now.
就是现在可以看到的位于右边的表
So, we're going to take that and we'll just,
现在要从这个表中提取信息
again I'm just going to call it T2.
暂称它为 t2
So let's pull from that.
从 t2 中进行提取
And we want to join on this table down here.
然后联接下边这个表
So, we're going to join on this table down here.
下面这个表
And I'll just stay that's with t3.
暂称它为 t3
So, basically this table right here is t2.
右边这个表是 t2
T3 was the table that we executed earlier,
t3 是我们之前执行的表
and we want to join where this max sales
现在我们想要使最大销售额
is equal to the sales that we saw in that earlier table,
等于前表中的销售额
and then pull both the region,
然后从联接表中提取相应区域
and the rep from the join.
和销售代表
So let's select.
现在进行选择
And essentially it really doesn't matter where we pull the region,
实质上要提取的地区
or whether we pull max sales, or total sales.
或者是否提取最大销售额或总销售额真的并不重要
The really important part here is the join portion.
表格连接部分是关键所在
So, from t2 we could pull the region name,
从 t2 可以提取区域名称
and from t2 we could also pull the max sales,
以及提取最大销售额
and then from t3 we need to pull the rep name.
然后从 t3 提取销售代表姓名
I'm just going to put that first.
我把它放在前面
Okay.
好
So, here we have the three parts that we need to pull,
这里就有了需要提取的三个部分
and then the important part here is how we join these two tables together.
接下来重要的是 如何将两个表连接起来
So, we have this table up here that has the region name,
上面这个表里有区域名称
and the max sales for a particular rep,
以及特定销售代表的最高销售额
and now essentially what we want to do is we want to join that.
现在需要联接两表
So, we want to join on the region name equal to the other region name.
即 t2.region_name = t3.region_name
And we want the max sales in t2
然后是 t2 的最大销售量
to be equal to the total sales in t3.
等于 t3 的总销售量
So, if the regions match then we know that we're looking at the right region.
如果区域匹配 就可以知道我们看到的是正确的区域
And if the max sales is equal to the total sales,
如果最大销售额等于销售总额
then that means that the max sales is equal
那么说明最大销售额
to the sales that we saw for a particular rep in this first table.
等于我们看到的第一个表里特定销售代表的销售额
So, it'll only pull essentially
因此
the sales representatives who have sales that are equal to these amounts,
仅提取销售额等于最大销售额的销售代表
and where they are in this region.
以及他们所在的区域
So basically, as you can see the Southeast has the highest.
可以看到 东南地区的销售额最高
So, maybe there is somebody in the Southeast who has this.
那么可能指向相应的销售代表
And if we didn't match on this region here,
如果没有对地区进行匹配
then potentially there could be multiple with the max sales that we have in the Midwest,
我们会得到中西部区域的多个最大销售额
but it's not the max for that region,
但不是该地区的最大销售额
this is the max for that region.
这是该地区的最大销售额
So, we can match on both the region and the sales amount.
因此我们连接两个地区和销售额
Cool. So, let's go ahead and run this.
然后运行
Okay.
好
So, it looks like we got four results.
可以看到我们得到四个结果
We have the Southeast, the Northeast,
包括东南、东北
the West, and the Midwest,
西部和中西部区域
and nothing else is showing there.
其它则消失不见
So there are those four regions.
这是四个区域
And here's essentially the max amount of sales
这是特定销售代表的最大销售额
by a particular rep and then the name of that representative.
这是销售代表的名字